export const questions = [
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the wine region of Tuscany located?",
    "choices": [
      "Portugal",
      "Italy",
      "Chile",
      "Germany"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "What is the main grape used in Champagne?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot grigio",
      "Merlot"
    ],
    "answer": "Chardonnay"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where does Malbec originally come from?",
    "choices": [
      "Argentina",
      "Chile",
      "Spain",
      "France"
    ],
    "answer": "France"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "What is a \"dry\" wine?",
    "choices": [
      "A wine with little to no sweetness",
      "Sparkling wine",
      "Sweet wine",
      "Fortified wine"
    ],
    "answer": "A wine with little to no sweetness"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "What is the primary flavor you might taste in a Sauvignon Blanc?",
    "choices": [
      "Molasses",
      "Citrus",
      "Chocolate",
      "Apple"
    ],
    "answer": "Citrus"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the wine region of Rioja located?",
    "choices": [
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Germany",
      "France"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "What is the term for the smell of a wine?",
    "choices": [
      "Taste",
      "Aroma",
      "Feel",
      "Location"
    ],
    "answer": "Aroma"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "What is the main grape in most red wines from Tuscany\u2019s Chianti region?",
    "choices": [
      "Sangiovese",
      "Syrah",
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Pinot Noir"
    ],
    "answer": "Sangiovese"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where does Riesling wine originate from?",
    "choices": [
      "Chile",
      "Portugal",
      "Germany",
      "Italy"
    ],
    "answer": "Germany"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "What French wine region is known for Riesling?",
    "choices": [
      "Bordeaux",
      "Provence",
      "Burgundy",
      "Alsace"
    ],
    "answer": "Alsace"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the wine region of Mendoza located?",
    "choices": [
      "Chile",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal",
      "Argentina"
    ],
    "answer": "Argentina"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "What is the purpose of swirling wine in a glass?",
    "choices": [
      "To release aromas",
      "To mix flavors",
      "To release color",
      "To cool it down"
    ],
    "answer": "To release aromas"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "How is port wine different from most wines?",
    "choices": [
      "It\u2019s made from one grape",
      "It\u2019s sweet and fortified",
      "It\u2019s aged in oak",
      "It\u2019s sparkling"
    ],
    "answer": "It\u2019s sweet and fortified"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the wine region of Marlborough located?",
    "choices": [
      "Chile",
      "France",
      "Portugal",
      "New Zealand"
    ],
    "answer": "New Zealand"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "What is the primary white grape in the Mosel region of Germany?",
    "choices": [
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Merlot",
      "Riesling",
      "Sauvignon Blanc"
    ],
    "answer": "Riesling"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with the Barolo wines of Piedmont, Italy?",
    "choices": [
      "Nebbiolo",
      "Dolcetto",
      "Sangiovese",
      "Barbera"
    ],
    "answer": "Nebbiolo"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the wine region of Stellenbosch located?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Portugal",
      "Germany",
      "South Africa"
    ],
    "answer": "South Africa"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which region is famous for its Tempranillo grape?",
    "choices": [
      "Napa Valley",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Rioja",
      "Tuscany"
    ],
    "answer": "Rioja"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "What is a key white grape grown in the Loire Valley of France?",
    "choices": [
      "Chardonnay",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Syrah",
      "Pinot Noir"
    ],
    "answer": "Sauvignon Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the wine region of Barossa Valley located?",
    "choices": [
      "Australia",
      "Spain",
      "Portugal",
      "Chile"
    ],
    "answer": "Australia"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the wine region of Douro Valley located?",
    "choices": [
      "Chile",
      "Germany",
      "Portugal",
      "France"
    ],
    "answer": "Portugal"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "What is the primary grape in red wines from the Mendoza region of Argentina?",
    "choices": [
      "Merlot",
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Malbec"
    ],
    "answer": "Malbec"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the wine region of Willamette Valley located?",
    "choices": [
      "Oregon",
      "Portugal",
      "Italy",
      "Spain"
    ],
    "answer": "Oregon"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is Screaming Eagle produced?",
    "choices": [
      "Sonoma Valley",
      "Washington State",
      "Portugal",
      "Napa Valley"
    ],
    "answer": "Napa Valley"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is Harlan produced?",
    "choices": [
      "Italy",
      "Finger Lakes",
      "Spain",
      "Napa Valley"
    ],
    "answer": "Napa Valley"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is Scarecrow produced?",
    "choices": [
      "Napa Valley",
      "Canada",
      "Chile",
      "Sonoma County"
    ],
    "answer": "Napa Valley"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which red grape is key to the wines of Brunello di Montalcino in Italy?",
    "choices": [
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Nebbiolo",
      "Sangiovese"
    ],
    "answer": "Sangiovese"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the wine region of Margaret River located?",
    "choices": [
      "Southern Italy",
      "Western Australia",
      "Western Portugal",
      "Northern California"
    ],
    "answer": "Western Australia"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which red grape is central to the wines of Beaujolais, France?",
    "choices": [
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Syrah",
      "Gamay",
      "Sauvignon Blanc"
    ],
    "answer": "Gamay"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which parent company produces la Grande Dame Champagne?",
    "choices": [
      "Lurton",
      "Bertrand",
      "Veuve Cliquot",
      "Moet"
    ],
    "answer": "Veuve Cliquot"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Niagara Escarpment?",
    "choices": [
      "Ontario",
      "Quebec",
      "Montana",
      "Lake Erie"
    ],
    "answer": "Ontario"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Frasier Valley?",
    "choices": [
      "Western Chile",
      "Southern Italy",
      "British Columbia",
      "Ohio River Valley"
    ],
    "answer": "British Columbia"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Who makes Clos St. Hune?",
    "choices": [
      "Hugel",
      "Trimbach",
      "Deiss",
      "Leroy"
    ],
    "answer": "Trimbach"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the premier cru of Clos St. Jacques?",
    "choices": [
      "Chablis",
      "Morey St. Denis",
      "Gevery Chambertin",
      "Mosel Valley"
    ],
    "answer": "Gevery Chambertin"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Morgon?",
    "choices": [
      "Provence",
      "Languedoc",
      "Beaujolais",
      "Bordeaux"
    ],
    "answer": "Beaujolais"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Juli\u00e9nas?",
    "choices": [
      "Chablis",
      "Little Rock",
      "Beaujolais",
      "Macon"
    ],
    "answer": "Beaujolais"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Chiroubles?",
    "choices": [
      "Germany",
      "Beaujolais",
      "Savoie",
      "Bordeaux"
    ],
    "answer": "Beaujolais"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Fleurie?",
    "choices": [
      "Bordeaux",
      "Savoie",
      "Beaujolais",
      "Champagne"
    ],
    "answer": "Beaujolais"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Alte Reben on a German wine label means what?",
    "choices": [
      "Vines over 20 years old",
      "Vines over 50 years old",
      "New vines",
      "Old vines"
    ],
    "answer": "Old vines"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What are the soils of Santorini?",
    "choices": [
      "Alluvial",
      "Volcanic",
      "Granite",
      "Gneiss"
    ],
    "answer": "Volcanic"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which country commands the highest price per bottle on average in the world?",
    "choices": [
      "USA",
      "Portugal",
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand"
    ],
    "answer": "New Zealand"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Who makes the wine \"g-max\"?",
    "choices": [
      "Doctor Bernkastler",
      "Weingut Keller",
      "Dr. Loosen",
      "Weingut Wittmann"
    ],
    "answer": "Weingut Keller"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What is the grape of Chinon blanc?",
    "choices": [
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc"
    ],
    "answer": "Chenin Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What is Hungary's largest region?",
    "choices": [
      "Kuns\u00e1g",
      "Sopron",
      "Bern",
      "Mosel"
    ],
    "answer": "Kuns\u00e1g"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What is the southern most AOP of the Northern Rh\u00f4ne Valley?",
    "choices": [
      "Hermitage",
      "Southern Plains",
      "St. Joseph",
      "St-P\u00e9ray"
    ],
    "answer": "St-P\u00e9ray"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What grape is used for Klevener de Heiligenstein?",
    "choices": [
      "Reisling",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Savagnin rose"
    ],
    "answer": "Savagnin rose"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Bodegas Chacra located?",
    "choices": [
      "Argentina",
      "Chile",
      "Italy",
      "Spain"
    ],
    "answer": "Argentina"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "The alluvial plain of what river is found in Emilia Romagna?",
    "choices": [
      "New Gusto",
      "Nile",
      "Po",
      "Mosel"
    ],
    "answer": "Po"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What growth in the Bordeaux classification is Ch\u00e2teau Palmer?",
    "choices": [
      "2nd",
      "Cru Bourgeois",
      "3rd",
      "None"
    ],
    "answer": "3rd"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What growth in the Bordeaux classification is Ch\u00e2teau Pontet-Canet?",
    "choices": [
      "3rd",
      "5th",
      "2nd",
      "6th"
    ],
    "answer": "5th"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What growth in the Bordeaux classification is Ch\u00e2teau Kirwan?",
    "choices": [
      "4th",
      "Super Second",
      "3rd",
      "Cru Bourgeois"
    ],
    "answer": "3rd"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What growth in the Bordeaux classification is Ch\u00e2teau Lascombes?",
    "choices": [
      "3rd",
      "8th",
      "5th",
      "2nd"
    ],
    "answer": "2nd"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Ch\u00e2teau Bouscaut located?",
    "choices": [
      "Provence",
      "Jura",
      "Burgundy",
      "Graves"
    ],
    "answer": "Graves"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Domaine de Chevalier located?",
    "choices": [
      "Chinon, France",
      "Graves, France",
      "SW France",
      "Cadiz, Spain"
    ],
    "answer": "Graves, France"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Ch\u00e2teau Pape-Cl\u00e9ment located?",
    "choices": [
      "Burgundy",
      "Graves",
      "Loire Valley",
      "Pomerol"
    ],
    "answer": "Graves"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is ch\u00e2teau Sainte-Roseline located?",
    "choices": [
      "Savoie",
      "Provence",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Mosel"
    ],
    "answer": "Provence"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Cote de Lechet located?",
    "choices": [
      "Provence",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Champagne",
      "Chablis"
    ],
    "answer": "Chablis"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Vaucopins located?",
    "choices": [
      "Chablis",
      "Champagne",
      "Levant",
      "South Africa"
    ],
    "answer": "Chablis"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What is the min. ammount of Sangiovese for Vino Nobile di Montepulciano DOCG?",
    "choices": [
      "20 percent",
      "70 percent",
      "50 percent",
      "none"
    ],
    "answer": "70 percent"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Lake Balanton?",
    "choices": [
      "Romania",
      "Northern Chile",
      "Eastern Italy",
      "West Hungary"
    ],
    "answer": "West Hungary"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Sea breezes called Meltemi are found where?",
    "choices": [
      "Spain",
      "Chile",
      "Portugal",
      "Greece"
    ],
    "answer": "Greece"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Anisette from?",
    "choices": [
      "Portugal",
      "Italy",
      "Germany",
      "France"
    ],
    "answer": "France"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Galliano from?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Italy",
      "Chile",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Ouzo from?",
    "choices": [
      "Greece",
      "France",
      "Chile",
      "Spain"
    ],
    "answer": "Greece"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Passione Nera from?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Chile",
      "Germany",
      "Italy"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What is Orujo?",
    "choices": [
      "Argentinian vodka",
      "Morroccan pomace brandy",
      "Spanish pomace brandy",
      "German schnapps"
    ],
    "answer": "Spanish pomace brandy"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What river runs through Rioja?",
    "choices": [
      "Ebro",
      "Ombrone",
      "Rhone",
      "Tiber"
    ],
    "answer": "Ebro"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What river runs through Valtelina?",
    "choices": [
      "Loess",
      "Hudson",
      "Po",
      "Adda"
    ],
    "answer": "Adda"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What river runs through Cahors?",
    "choices": [
      "Lot",
      "Algarve",
      "Porto",
      "Vienne"
    ],
    "answer": "Lot"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What river runs through Vouvray?",
    "choices": [
      "Brenne",
      "Hudson",
      "Riesling",
      "Po"
    ],
    "answer": "Brenne"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What river runs through Barbaresco?",
    "choices": [
      "Adda",
      "Tanaro",
      "Russian",
      "Italian"
    ],
    "answer": "Tanaro"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What river runs through Tokaj?",
    "choices": [
      "Po",
      "Carpathian",
      "Bodrog",
      "Nebbiolo"
    ],
    "answer": "Bodrog"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Guadalete River?",
    "choices": [
      "Jerez",
      "Madrid",
      "Italy",
      "Barcelona"
    ],
    "answer": "Jerez"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Piave River?",
    "choices": [
      "Portugal",
      "Veneto",
      "Umbria",
      "Liguria"
    ],
    "answer": "Veneto"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Lake Neuchatel?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Germany",
      "Chile",
      "Switzerland"
    ],
    "answer": "Switzerland"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Lake Balaton?",
    "choices": [
      "Portugal",
      "Italy",
      "Chile",
      "Hungary"
    ],
    "answer": "Hungary"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Lake Trasimeno?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Portugal",
      "Spain",
      "Italy"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where are the Dentelles Mountians located?",
    "choices": [
      "Northern Chile",
      "Southern France",
      "Western Portugal",
      "Spain"
    ],
    "answer": "Southern France"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Mt. Lofty Ranges located?",
    "choices": [
      "McLaren Vale, Australia",
      "Porto, Portugal",
      "Santiago, Chile",
      "Southern France"
    ],
    "answer": "McLaren Vale, Australia"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the the Great Dividing Range located?",
    "choices": [
      "NSW, Australia",
      "Mosel, Germany",
      "Western Italy",
      "Chile"
    ],
    "answer": "NSW, Australia"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Finger Lakes AVA?",
    "choices": [
      "Virginia",
      "Ohio",
      "Vermont",
      "New York"
    ],
    "answer": "New York"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which parent company produces Bond?",
    "choices": [
      "Cakebread",
      "Rodney Strong",
      "Mateus",
      "Harlan"
    ],
    "answer": "Harlan"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which grape is used in the white wines of Soave?",
    "choices": [
      "Pinot Gris",
      "Riesling",
      "Garganega",
      "Chardonnay"
    ],
    "answer": "Garganega"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which white grape is most associated with the Rueda region of Spain?",
    "choices": [
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Syrah",
      "Verdejo",
      "Merlot"
    ],
    "answer": "Verdejo"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is South Africa's southernmost wine district?",
    "choices": [
      "Cape Aghuilas",
      "Porto",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Cape Town"
    ],
    "answer": "Cape Aghuilas"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What grand cru site is Trimbach's Clos-Ste-Hune located?",
    "choices": [
      "Altenberg de Bergheim",
      "Rosacker",
      "Kaefferkopf",
      "Strousbourg"
    ],
    "answer": "Rosacker"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the largest grand cru of Alsace?",
    "choices": [
      "Deiss",
      "Rangen",
      "Vosges",
      "Schlossberg"
    ],
    "answer": "Schlossberg"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Byrrh produced?",
    "choices": [
      "Oregon, USA",
      "Madrid, Spain",
      "Rousillon, France",
      "Ontario, Canada"
    ],
    "answer": "Rousillon, France"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "How long is Napolean Armagnac aged for?",
    "choices": [
      "9 to 12 years",
      "1 year",
      "2 years",
      "4 - 9 years"
    ],
    "answer": "4 - 9 years"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Trois Pommes?",
    "choices": [
      "Calvados",
      "Jura",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Cognac"
    ],
    "answer": "Calvados"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "How long is Brandy de Jerez solera gran reserva aged for?",
    "choices": [
      "More than 10 years",
      "More than 3 years",
      "More than 20 years",
      "More than 50 years"
    ],
    "answer": "More than 3 years" 
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Haux?",
    "choices": [
      "Nebbiolo based quinquina",
      "Riesling based spirit",
      "Chilean Brandy",
      "French eau de vie"
    ],
    "answer": "French eau de vie"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is la vieille cure?",
    "choices": [
      "Eau de Vie",
      "Scotch",
      "Herbal liquer from France",
      "Herbal liqueur from Germany"
    ],
    "answer": "Herbal liquer from France"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the term for semi-sparkling wine in Spain?",
    "choices": [
      "Vino de aguja",
      "Cider",
      "tresterbrand",
      "Cremant Blanc"
    ],
    "answer": "Vino de aguja"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Define bouvreux.",
    "choices": [
      "The 'second crop' of Champagne",
      "The overgrowth in a vineyard",
      "Italian Brandy",
      "Australian Schnapps"
    ],
    "answer": "The 'second crop' of Champagne"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the maximum residual sugar of Champagne base wine?",
    "choices": [
      "2 g/l",
      "50 g/l",
      "20 g/l",
      "10 g/l"
    ],
    "answer": "10 g/l"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Define prise de mousse.",
    "choices": [
      "Merlot than is late harvested",
      "The Second fermentation in Champagne",
      "Fine bubbles in sparkling wine",
      "The first fermentation of Champagne"
    ],
    "answer": "Second fermentation in Champagne"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What DOC is responsible for quality sparkling wine in Portugal?",
    "choices": [
      "Algarve",
      "Duoro",
      "Porto",
      "Tavora-Varosa"
    ],
    "answer": "Tavora-Varosa"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the term for sparkling wine from Tokaji, Hungary?",
    "choices": [
      "Carpathian sparkling",
      "Luzo",
      "Pezsg\u0151",
      "Cremant"
    ],
    "answer": "Pezsg\u0151"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which AOP is known as Marque Nationale \u2013 appellation contr\u00f4l\u00e9e?",
    "choices": [
      "Cremant de Luxembourg",
      "1855 Bordeaux Classification",
      "Burgundy Grand Cru",
      "Cremant du Jura"
    ],
    "answer": "Cremant de Luxembourg"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What grape varietals are allowed for Gaillac mousseaux?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc and Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Noir and Chardonnay",
      "Syrah and Grenache",
      "Mauzac"
      
    ],
    "answer": "Mauzac"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "How long must a Colheita Madeira be aged?",
    "choices": [
      "3 yrs",
      "5 yrs",
      "7 yrs",
      "10 yrs"
    ],
    "answer": "5 yrs"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the minimum oak aging for Macvin du Jura?",
    "choices": [
      "12 months",
      "18 months",
      "3 years",
      "10 years"
    ],
    "answer": "12 mos"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which producer has the term Almacenista trademarked?",
    "choices": [
      "Neipoort",
      "Deiss",
      "Lustau",
      "Mateus"
    ],
    "answer": "Lustau"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the minimum ABV of Sauternes?",
    "choices": [
      "15% (12% acquired)",
      "18%",
      "12% (8% acquired)",
      "20%"
    ],
    "answer": "15% (12% acquired)"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the min. aging requirment's for estufagem Madeira?",
    "choices": [
      "2 yrs",
      "3 yrs",
      "5 yrs.",
      "10 yrs."
    ],
    "answer": "Estufagem: 2 yrs"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the min aging req's for canteiro Madeira?",
    "choices": [
      "6 months",
      "1 yr.",
      "2 yrs.",
      "3 ys"
    ],
    "answer": "Canteiro: 3 ys"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "When is the vine most succeptable to eutypa dieback?",
    "choices": [
      "During planting",
      "During flowering",
      "At harvest",
      "Immediately after pruning"
    ],
    "answer": "Immediately after pruning"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the simplest form of spur-pruning/head-training?",
    "choices": [
      "Double Curtain",
      "Gobelet",
      "Napa Valley Hanger",
      "VSP"
    ],
    "answer": "Gobelet"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Define microbullage.",
    "choices": [
      "Fermentation",
      "Planting",
      "Refining",
      "Micro-oxygenation"
    ],
    "answer": "Micro-oxygenation"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the largest demarcated region in Europe?",
    "choices": [
      "Provence",
      "Burgundy",
      "La Mancha",
      "Puglia"
    ],
    "answer": "La Mancha"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which do is located directly north of Ribera del Duero?",
    "choices": [
      "Arlanza",
      "Rioja",
      "Madrid",
      "Rueda"
    ],
    "answer": "Arlanza"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Zibbibo?",
    "choices": [
      "National cocktail of Andorra",
      "Synonym for Muscat",
      "Term for harvesting",
      "Name of a producer in Sicily"
    ],
    "answer": "Synonym for muscat"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the main grape varietal and minimum % for Bandol rouge?",
    "choices": [
      "100% Mourvedre",
      "50% min. Mourvedre",
      "60% min. Grenache",
      "100% Grenache"
    ],
    "answer": "50% min. Mourvedre"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Who produces Edelkeur?",
    "choices": [
      "E & J",
      "Nolly Pratt",
      "Nederburg",
      "Constantia"
    ],
    "answer": "Nederburg"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Who produces Celebris?",
    "choices": [
      "Selosse",
      "Jacquart",
      "Moet",
      "Gossett"
    ],
    "answer": "Gossett"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the Yorkville Highlands AVA?",
    "choices": [
      "Mendocino County",
      "Napa Valley",
      "Sonoma Mountian",
      "Lake County"
    ],
    "answer": "Mendocino County"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where are the Gimblett Gravels?",
    "choices": [
      "Auckland",
      "Hawkes Bay",
      "Martinborough",
      "Otago"
    ],
    "answer": "Hawkes Bay"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Keuka Lake?",
    "choices": [
      "Finger Lakes, NY",
      "Southern Chile",
      "Shenandoah Valley, VA",
      "Central Germany"
    ],
    "answer": "Finger Lakes, NY"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Kwazulu Natal?",
    "choices": [
      "Portugal",
      "South Africa",
      "Spain",
      "Argentina"
    ],
    "answer": "South Africa"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Who produces Hill of Grace?",
    "choices": [
      "Henshke",
      "Porters",
      "Torbreck",
      "Penfolds"
    ],
    "answer": "Henshke"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Malleco?",
    "choices": [
      "Central Spain",
      "Northern Argentina",
      "Southern Chile",
      "Southern Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Southern Chile"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which was the best vintage for the medoc: 1997, 1998, 1999 or 2000?",
    "choices": [
      "1998",
      "1997",
      "2000",
      "1999"
    ],
    "answer": "2000"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What are the 2 main varietals for Jurancon?",
    "choices": [
      "Gros and Petite Manseng",
      "Pinot Noir and Chardonnay",
      "Petite Manseng and Petit Verdot",
      "Gros Plant and Muscadet"
    ],
    "answer": "Gros and Petite Manseng"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Kangaroo Island?",
    "choices": [
      "Tazmania",
      "South Australia",
      "New Zealand Coast",
      "South Africa"
    ],
    "answer": "South Australia"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What river flows through Valtellina?",
    "choices": [
      "Ombrone",
      "Tanaro",
      "Po",
      "Adda"
    ],
    "answer": "Adda"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Lake Bodensee?",
    "choices": [
      "Ahr, Germany",
      "Alsace, France",
      "Nahe, Germany",
      "Baden, Germany"
    ],
    "answer": "Baden, Germany"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where would you find the vineyard Graacher Domprobst?",
    "choices": [
      "Mosel",
      "Nahe",
      "Rheingau",
      "Rheinhessen"
    ],
    "answer": "Mosel"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the ungrafted varietal found in Colares?",
    "choices": [
      "Romandolo",
      "Ruiz",
      "Romorantin",
      "Ramisco"
    ],
    "answer": "Ramisco"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is St. Germains elderflower liquer produced?",
    "choices": [
      "Eastern France",
      "Northern Spain",
      "Southern Germany",
      "West Coast of Italy"
    ],
    "answer": "Eastern France"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Is Setubal west, north or south of Lisbon?",
    "choices": [
      "Same Latitude",
      "West",
      "South",
      "North"
    ],
    "answer": "South"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Simalkeeman?",
    "choices": [
      "Ontario",
      "British Columbia",
      "Finger Lakes",
      "Nova Scotia"
    ],
    "answer": "British columbia"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Minimum aging requirement for colheita port?",
    "choices": [
      "3 years",
      "5 years",
      "6 years",
      "7 years"
    ],
    "answer": "7 years"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Clos des Ormes?",
    "choices": [
      "Morey St Denis",
      "Chambolle Musigny",
      "Haut Poitou",
      "Hautes Cotes de Nuits"
    ],
    "answer": "Morey St Denis"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Beaumont-su-Vesle?",
    "choices": [
      "Chablis",
      "SW France",
      "Anjou",
      "Champagne"
    ],
    "answer": "Champagne"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What mountain range separates Napa and Sonoma counties?",
    "choices": [
      "Mayayacamas",
      "Dentelles",
      "Sonoma Mountian",
      "Vaca Range"
    ],
    "answer": "Mayayacamas"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which AOC is based upon the Romorantin varietal?",
    "choices": [
      "Cour-Cheverny",
      "Vienne",
      "Cour de Cuvee",
      "Haut Poitou"
    ],
    "answer": "Cour-Cheverny"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Dry white wines from Cerons are sold under which AOC?",
    "choices": [
      "Bordeaux AOC",
      "Graves AOC",
      "Haut-Medoc AOC",
      "Entre-deux-Mers AOC"
    ],
    "answer": "Graves AOC"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Grattalops?",
    "choices": [
      "Rioja, Spain",
      "Priorat, Spain",
      "Madrid, Spain",
      "Porto, Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Priorat, Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Valdizarbe?",
    "choices": [
      "Portugal",
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Mexico"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Who makes Nec Plus Ultra?",
    "choices": [
      "Moet",
      "Selosse",
      "Bruno Paillard",
      "Gratien"
    ],
    "answer": "Bruno Paillard"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What river does Toro D.O. reside on?",
    "choices": [
      "Duero",
      "Guadalette",
      "Ebro",
      "Ombrone"
    ],
    "answer": "Duero"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What island did Machico burn to the ground in 1419?",
    "choices": [
      "Pellee Island",
      "South Island",
      "Madeira",
      "Canary Islands"
    ],
    "answer": "Madeira"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What river bisects Sachsen?",
    "choices": [
      "Rhine",
      "Rhone",
      "Ebro",
      "Elbe"
    ],
    "answer": "Elbe"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Who produces Redigaffi?",
    "choices": [
      "Tua Rita",
      "Morrisfarms",
      "Sandrone",
      "Gaja"
    ],
    "answer": "Tua Rita"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What are the aging requirements for gran reserva Cava?",
    "choices": [
      "3 months on the lees",
      "18 months on the lees",
      "24 months on the lees",
      "30 months on the lees"
    ],
    "answer": "30 months on the lees"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Clos de Tart is a monopole for which producer?",
    "choices": [
      "Leroy",
      "Mommessin",
      "DRC",
      "Cave de Borgogne"
    ],
    "answer": "Mommessin"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the vineyard Les Narbantons?",
    "choices": [
      "Chablis",
      "Champagne",
      "Morey St. Denis",
      "Savingy-les-Beaune"
    ],
    "answer": "Savingy-les-Beaune"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which producer is responsible for Torgiano?",
    "choices": [
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Nebbiolo",
      "Argentina",
      "Lungarotti"
    ],
    "answer": "Lungarotti"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where are the Levant winds found?",
    "choices": [
      "Galicia",
      "Toro",
      "Portugal",
      "Andalucia"
    ],
    "answer": "Andalucia"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which slovenian region borders Collio?",
    "choices": [
      "Distania",
      "Western Plains",
      "Primorska",
      "Posovdje"
    ],
    "answer": "Primorska"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which river influences the Tokaj region?",
    "choices": [
      "Carpathian",
      "Debina",
      "Bodrog",
      "Balanton"
    ],
    "answer": "Bodrog"
  },

  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the Lac du Bourget?",
    "choices": [
      "Belgium",
      "Quebec",
      "Savoie",
      "Champagne"
    ],
    "answer": "Savoie"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which sub-region of Rias Baixas sit on the Minho River?",
    "choices": [
      "Ribiera Sacra",
      "Coronado",
      "Montero",
      "Condado del Tea"
    ],
    "answer": "Condado del Tea"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the river of Ribatejano?",
    "choices": [
      "Ebro",
      "Tejo",
      "Duero",
      "Tavora"
    ],
    "answer": "Tejo"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which is a sub region of Adelaide Hlls?",
    "choices": [
      "Limnio",
      "Picadilly Valley",
      "Lungarotti",
      "Kangaroo Valley"
    ],
    "answer": "Picadilly Valley"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which river runs through Chinon?",
    "choices": [
      "Charmes",
      "Loir",
      "Brenne",
      "Vienne"
    ],
    "answer": "Vienne"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Banks Penninsula?",
    "choices": [
      "Martinborough, NZ",
      "Sonoma County, CA",
      "Canterbury, NZ",
      "Columbia Valley, WA"
    ],
    "answer": "Canterbury, NZ"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Boutenac?",
    "choices": [
      "Corbieres",
      "Colores",
      "Canterburry",
      "Toulouse"
    ],
    "answer": "Corbieres"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which Rias Baixas sub-region is the most northernly?",
    "choices": [
      "Condado de Haza",
      "Ribeira do Ulla",
      "Condado del Tea",
      "O Rosal"
    ],
    "answer": "Ribeira do Ulla"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Nagambie Lakes?",
    "choices": [
      "Barossa Valley, South Australia",
      "Goulbourn Valley, Victoria",
      "Yarra Valley, Victoria",
      "Hunter Valley, NSW"
    ],
    "answer": "Goulbourn Valley, Victoria"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Ch\u00e2teau Tahlbik?",
    "choices": [
      "Barossa Valley, South Australia",
      "Mornington Peninsula, Victoria",
      "Yarra Valley, Victoria",
      "Goulbourn Valley, Victoria"
    ],
    "answer": "Goulbourn Valley, Victoria"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What are the grape parents of Zweigelt?",
    "choices": [
      "Blaufrankisch & Syrah",
      "Blaufrankisch & Pinot Noir",
      "Blaufrankisch & St. Laurent",
      "Chardonnay & Riesling"
    ],
    "answer": "Blaufrankisch & St. Laurent"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which lake does Bianco di Custoza reside on?",
    "choices": [
      "Lago di Trasimeno",
      "Lago di Como",
      "Lago di Ciccio",
      "Lago di Garda"
    ],
    "answer": "Lago di Garda"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is east Taratahi/Gladstone?",
    "choices": [
      "Canterberry",
      "Wellington",
      "Auckland",
      "Otago"
    ],
    "answer": "Wellington"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Germany's only anbaugebeit without an erste lage site?",
    "choices": [
      "Baden",
      "Alsace",
      "Ahr",
      "Hessische-Bergstra\u00dfe"
    ],
    "answer": "Hessische-Bergstra\u00dfe"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Cape Farewell?",
    "choices": [
      "Otago",
      "Nelson",
      "Auckland",
      "Sunbury"
    ],
    "answer": "Nelson"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Schilcher?",
    "choices": [
      "Ros\u00e9 from Styria, Germany",
      "Sparkling wine from Germany",
      "Brandy from Germany",
      "Fortified wine from Tuscany"
    ],
    "answer": "Ros\u00e9 from Styria, Germany"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the white grape of Crete?",
    "choices": [
      "Chardonnay",
      "Vilana",
      "Verdelho",
      "Sauvignon Blanc"
    ],
    "answer": "Vilana"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "How long must Rivesaltes hors d'auge be aged?",
    "choices": [
      "2 years",
      "3 years",
      "4years",
      "5 years"
    ],
    "answer": "5 years"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is an alternative name for the crown gall vine disease?",
    "choices": [
      "Black soiled",
      "Aspersion",
      "Black knot",
      "Black root"
    ],
    "answer": "Black knot"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the only Ch\u00e2teau to dissapear from the 1855 classification?",
    "choices": [
      "Ch\u00e2teau Mouton Noir",
      "Ch\u00e2teau Malescot",
      "Ch\u00e2teau Charmes",
      "Ch\u00e2teau Dubignon"
    ],
    "answer": "Ch\u00e2teau Dubignon"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the minimum residual sugar for Muscat Beaumes de Venise?",
    "choices": [
      "Min. 100 rs g/l",
      "Min. 120 rs g/l",
      "Min. 140 rs g/l",
      "Min. 160 rs g/l"
    ],
    "answer": "Min. 100 rs g/l"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which Provencal wine is bottled in bowling pin shaped bottle?",
    "choices": [
      "Domaine Ott",
      "Domaine Seysel",
      "Ch\u00e2teau de Pibarnon",
      "Domaine de la Brillane"
    ],
    "answer": "Domaine Ott"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is flascheng\u00e4rung?",
    "choices": [
      "Pomace brandy base wine",
      "Late harvest Riesling",
      "Bottle-fermented Sekt",
      "Fortified wine"
    ],
    "answer": "Bottle-fermented Sekt"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Cape Canaile?",
    "choices": [
      "Rousillon",
      "Avignon",
      "Cassis",
      "Bandol"
    ],
    "answer": "Cassis"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the mountain range of Gigondas?",
    "choices": [
      "Masif Central",
      "Dentelles",
      "Sierra de Gredos",
      "Alps"
    ],
    "answer": "Dentelles"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the commune of Pupullin?",
    "choices": [
      "Arbois",
      "Savoie",
      "Champagne",
      "Burgundy"
    ],
    "answer": "Arbois"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the river of Gigondas?",
    "choices": [
      "Brenne",
      "Lot",
      "Ouveze",
      "Ombrone"
    ],
    "answer": "Ouveze"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is produced in Sterea Ellada?",
    "choices": [
      "Sparkling wine",
      "Retsina",
      "Tempranillo",
      "Cider"
    ],
    "answer": "Retsina"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Ch\u00e2teau Simone?",
    "choices": [
      "Frontignan",
      "Cassis",
      "Bandol",
      "Palette"
    ],
    "answer": "Palette"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Ch\u00e2teau de Saint Cosme?",
    "choices": [
      "Corsica",
      "Hermitage",
      "St. Joseph",
      "Gigondas"
    ],
    "answer": "Gigondas"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the synonym for Blaufr\u00e4nkisch in Hungary?",
    "choices": [
      "K\u00e9kfrankos",
      "Grenache",
      "Merlot",
      "Kunsag"
    ],
    "answer": "K\u00e9kfrankos"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the synonym for Vermentino in Provence?",
    "choices": [
      "Romorantin",
      "Rolle",
      "Rousette",
      "Sauvignon Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Rolle"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where would you find R\u00e1k\u00f3czy\u2019s original classification?",
    "choices": [
      "Burgundy",
      "Graves",
      "Balanton",
      "Tokaji"
    ],
    "answer": "Tokaji"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the St. Christophe plateau?",
    "choices": [
      "St. Emilion",
      "Graves",
      "Burgundy",
      "Provence"
    ],
    "answer": "St. Emilion"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the second wine of Branaire-Ducru?",
    "choices": [
      "Duluc",
      "Dubois",
      "Descartes",
      "Devonshire"
    ],
    "answer": "Duluc"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is St Roman AOP?",
    "choices": [
      "Germany",
      "Portugal",
      "Spain",
      "Cote de Beaune"
    ],
    "answer": "Cote de Beaune"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the vineyard of Pisse Veille?",
    "choices": [
      "Morey St. Denis",
      "Brouilly",
      "Provence",
      "Roussillon"
    ],
    "answer": "Brouilly"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the synonym for Refosco in Carso DOC?",
    "choices": [
      "Rioja Negra",
      "Nebbiolo",
      "Buscotto",
      "Terrano"
    ],
    "answer": "Terrano"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Moquegua Valley?",
    "choices": [
      "Peru",
      "Chile",
      "USA",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Peru"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Jegbor?",
    "choices": [
      "Ice wine in Hungary",
      "Ice wine in Bulgaria",
      "Sparkling wine in Hungary",
      "Late harvest wine in France"
    ],
    "answer": "Ice wine in Hungary"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the main grape varietal of the Zitsa region?",
    "choices": [
      "Debina",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Fiano",
      "Croatina"
    ],
    "answer": "Debina"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where are the Tro\u00f6dos Mountains?",
    "choices": [
      "Montenegro",
      "Cyprus",
      "Germany",
      "Greece"
    ],
    "answer": "Cyprus"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Loramie Creek AVA?",
    "choices": [
      "Maryland",
      "New York",
      "California",
      "Ohio"
    ],
    "answer": "Ohio"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the Gulf Saint Vincent?",
    "choices": [
      "Victoria",
      "Adelaide",
      "Barossa Valley",
      "Tasmania"
    ],
    "answer": "Adelaide"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Omar Khayyam?",
    "choices": [
      "Sparkling wine from India",
      "Fortified wine from Spain",
      "Still wine from Morroco",
      "German Schnapps"
    ],
    "answer": "Sparkling wine from India"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Producer of les Clos St. Hilaire?",
    "choices": [
      "Moet & Chandon",
      "Billecart-Salmon",
      "Selosse",
      "Aggrapart"
    ],
    "answer": "Billecart-Salmon"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where would you find Nosiola growing?",
    "choices": [
      "Peidmont",
      "Tuscany",
      "Veneto",
      "Trentino-Alto Adige"
    ],
    "answer": "Trentino-Alto Adige"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Broke Fordwich is a subregion of which region?",
    "choices": [
      "Tasmania",
      "Hunter Valley",
      "Mornington Peninsula",
      "Margaret River"
    ],
    "answer": "Hunter Valley"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is El Hierro located?",
    "choices": [
      "Andalucia",
      "Porto",
      "Canary Islands",
      "Madeira"
    ],
    "answer": "Canary Islands"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the Catoctin AVA?",
    "choices": [
      "Maryland",
      "California",
      "Oregon",
      "NY"
    ],
    "answer": "Maryland"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the grape of Fara DOC?",
    "choices": [
      "Nebbiolo",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Barbera"
    ],
    "answer": "Nebbiolo"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "If a wine is labeled lagrima, what does this indicate?",
    "choices": [
      "English port",
      "White Madeira",
      "Dry white port",
      "Sweet white port"
    ],
    "answer": "Sweet white port"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Completer grown?",
    "choices": [
      "Portugal",
      "Switzerland",
      "Austria",
      "Hungary"
    ],
    "answer": "Switzerland"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where would you find the Solano winds?",
    "choices": [
      "Rioja",
      "Rueda",
      "Ribatejo",
      "Chile"
    ],
    "answer": "Rioja"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the Mesilla Valley AVA?",
    "choices": [
      "California",
      "Maine",
      "New Mexico",
      "Washington"
    ],
    "answer": "New Mexico"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the premier cru of Sillery?",
    "choices": [
      "Montagne de Reims",
      "Cote de Bars",
      "Vall\u00e9e de la Marne",
      "Hautes Cotes de Nuits"
    ],
    "answer": "Montagne de Reims"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the premier cru of Bouzy?",
    "choices": [
      "Montagne de Reims",
      "Cote de Bars",
      "Vall\u00e9e de la Marne",
      "Hautes Cotes de Nuits"
    ],
    "answer": "Montagne de Reims"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the premier cru of Ambonnay?",
    "choices": [
      "Montagne de Reims",
      "Cote de Bars",
      "Vall\u00e9e de la Marne",
      "Hautes Cotes de Nuits"
    ],
    "answer": "Montagne de Reims"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the premier cru of Tours-sur-Marne?",
    "choices": [
      "Orleans",
      "Chablis",
      "Cotes de Blancs",
      "Vall\u00e9e de la Marne"
    ],
    "answer": "Vall\u00e9e de la Marne"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the premier cru of Aux Combottes?",
    "choices": [
      "Vosne Romanee",
      "Chambolle Musigny",
      "Gevery Chambertin",
      "Macon"
    ],
    "answer": "Gevery Chambertin"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the premier cru of Les Cazetieres?",
    "choices": [
      "Vosne Romanee",
      "Chambolle Musigny",
      "Gevery Chambertin",
      "Macon"
    ],
    "answer": "Gevery Chambertin"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What region does the the Cantabrian Mountains protect?",
    "choices": [
      "Grattalops",
      "Valencia",
      "Rioja",
      "Jerez"
    ],
    "answer": "Rioja"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Who makes quinta da ervamoira?",
    "choices": [
      "Ramos-pinto",
      "Australia",
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Napa Valley"
    ],
    "answer": "Ramos-pinto"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "The bass straight separates which two land masses?",
    "choices": [
      "Alsace",
      "Australia and Tasmania",
      "France",
      "Cabernet Sauvignon"
    ],
    "answer": "Australia and Tasmania"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Wahgunyah is a sub-region of which major area?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Chile",
      "Rutherglen",
      "Germany"
    ],
    "answer": "Rutherglen"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What wind occurence impact western Australia?",
    "choices": [
      "Zonda",
      "Fremantle doctor",
      "Pacific breeze",
      "Petaluma Gap"
    ],
    "answer": "Fremantle doctor"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the C\u00f4tes du Couchois?",
    "choices": [
      "Jura",
      "Chablis",
      "Champagne",
      "Cote Chalonaise"
    ],
    "answer": "Cote Chalonaise"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which county is the Diablo Grande AVA in?",
    "choices": [
      "Napa county",
      "Lake county",
      "Santa Barbara county",
      "Sacramento county"
    ],
    "answer": "Sacramento county"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Ch\u00e2teau de Loei was the first commercial winery where?",
    "choices": [
      "Thailand",
      "Bhutan",
      "Peru",
      "Mexico"
    ],
    "answer": "Thailand"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which area of China has the most wineries and highest quality production levels?",
    "choices": [
      "Beijing peninsula",
      "Shandong province",
      "Hang Seng region",
      "Inner provinces"
    ],
    "answer": "Shandong province"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which river runs through the maremma?",
    "choices": [
      "Ombrone",
      "Tempranillo",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Tuscany"
    ],
    "answer": "Ombrone"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the tagus river?",
    "choices": [
      "Chile",
      "France",
      "Ribatejo",
      "Germany"
    ],
    "answer": "Ribatejo"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where would you find the grape Pontac?",
    "choices": [
      "Kwazulu Natal",
      "Stellenbosch",
      "Constantia",
      "Walker Bay"
    ],
    "answer": "Constantia"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Location of the Indre river.?",
    "choices": [
      "Torrainey",
      "Central Vineyards",
      "Champagne",
      "Haut Cotes de Nuits"
    ],
    "answer": "Torraine, Loire Valley"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is milk sherry?",
    "choices": [
      "Sherry and ice cream",
      "Sweetened Amontillado",
      "Milk infudes fino",
      "Montilla-Moriles wine"
    ],
    "answer": "Sweetened amontillado"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where would you find boulb\u00e8nes, aslar, and ribot soil types?",
    "choices": [
      "Entre-deux-Mers",
      "Pomerol",
      "Haut Medoc",
      "Cahors"
    ],
    "answer": "Entre-deux-Mers"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Who produces Cuv\u00e9e Orpale?",
    "choices": [
      "Gratien",
      "Moet & Chandon",
      "Union Champagne",
      "Selosse"
    ],
    "answer": "Union Champagne"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where are the pollino mountains?",
    "choices": [
      "Portugal",
      "France",
      "Calabria",
      "Italy"
    ],
    "answer": "Calabria"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Sea breezes called Meltemi are found where?",
    "choices": [
      "Chile",
      "France",
      "Corsica",
      "Greece"
    ],
    "answer": "Greece"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Alte reben on a German wine label means what?",
    "choices": [
      "Available overseas",
      "Dry",
      "Aged 10 years",
      "Old vines"
    ],
    "answer": "Old vines"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the most noteworthy area for the Glera varietal?",
    "choices": [
      "Adda",
      "Romarisco",
      "Rosacker",
      "Cartizze"
    ],
    "answer": "Cartizze"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Most planted grape in Piedmont?",
    "choices": [
      "Barbera",
      "Merlot",
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Pinot Noir"
    ],
    "answer": "Barbera"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Rota tent, produced from the Tintilla de Rota grape, is produced where?",
    "choices": [
      "Fortified wine from Lisbon",
      "Dessert wine from Romania",
      "Sparkling wine from Andorra",
      "Fortified wine from Jerez"
    ],
    "answer": "Fortified wine from Jerez"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the grape of Bugey-Manicle rouge?",
    "choices": [
      "Merlot",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Syrah"
    ],
    "answer": "Pinot Noir"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Mateus ros\u00e9?",
    "choices": [
      "Chilean Sparkling wine",
      "Rioja ros\u00e9",
      "Barbera based white wine",
      "Portugese ros\u00e9"
    ],
    "answer": "Portugese ros\u00e9"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the synonym for Garnacha in Toro?",
    "choices": [
      "Tinta Roriz",
      "Tinta Aragonez",
      "Tinto Fino",
      "Tinta Rotilla"
    ],
    "answer": "Tinta Aragonez"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the synonym for Mazuelo in Priorat?",
    "choices": [
      "Romorantin",
      "Cinsault",
      "Tempranillo",
      "Samso"
    ],
    "answer": "Samso"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which country commands the highest price per bottle on average in the world?",
    "choices": [
      "Chardonnay",
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "New Zealand",
      "Chile"
    ],
    "answer": "New Zealand"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the Coromandel Peninsula?",
    "choices": [
      "Martinborough",
      "Cooks Island",
      "Waikato/Bay of Plenty",
      "Auckland"
    ],
    "answer": "Waikato/Bay of Plenty"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What varietal is known as the green grape in South Africa?",
    "choices": [
      "Semillon",
      "Pinot Gris",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Pinotage"
    ],
    "answer": "Semillon"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which legally trademarked bottle shape is a copy of an ancient flagon?",
    "choices": [
      "Madeira",
      "Vin de Constance",
      "Tahitian Gold",
      "Tresterbrand"
    ],
    "answer": "Vin de Constance"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which native varietal does Domaine Carras blend into their wines?",
    "choices": [
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Pinot gris",
      "Limnio",
      "Kadarka"
    ],
    "answer": "Limnio"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What are the Vosges Mountians called in the Pfalz?",
    "choices": [
      "Ahr Range",
      "Haardt Hills",
      "Bodensee Hills",
      "Pfalz Peaks"
    ],
    "answer": "Haardt hills"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the synonmy for Chasselas in the Vaud region?",
    "choices": [
      "Chardonnay",
      "Dora Baltea",
      "Descartes",
      "Dorin"
    ],
    "answer": "Dorin"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which is the southernmost grand cru of Alsace?",
    "choices": [
      "Rangen",
      "Strousbourg",
      "Ochsle",
      "Schlossberg"
    ],
    "answer": "Rangen"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the most cultivated grape of Puliga?",
    "choices": [
      "Sangiovese",
      "Barbera",
      "Refosco",
      "Negroamaro"
    ],
    "answer": "Negroamaro"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which is a sub area of Curico Valley?",
    "choices": [
      "Puente Alto",
      "Lontue",
      "Tennarife",
      "Lusson"
    ],
    "answer": "Lontue"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Villarica?",
    "choices": [
      "Uruguay",
      "Paraguay",
      "Portugal",
      "Spain"
    ],
    "answer": "Paraguay"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Famatina Valley?",
    "choices": [
      "Santiago, Chile",
      "La Rioja, Argentina",
      "Patagonia, Argentina",
      "Santa Barbara, California"
    ],
    "answer": "La Rioja, Argentina"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Bodega Noemia?",
    "choices": [
      "Mendoza",
      "Patagonia",
      "San Juan",
      "Punete Alto"
    ],
    "answer": "Patagonia"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the offical subzone of Colli Orientali del Friuli-picolit docg ?",
    "choices": [
      "Verduzzo",
      "Veneto grande",
      "Cialla",
      "Po"
    ],
    "answer": "Cialla"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the river of the Valle d'Aosta?",
    "choices": [
      "Po",
      "Dora Baltea",
      "Adda",
      "Hudson"
    ],
    "answer": "Dora Baltea"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What was the first vintage of Tignanello?",
    "choices": [
      "1998",
      "1946",
      "1971",
      "1975"
    ],
    "answer": "1971"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the synonym for Garganega in Sicily?",
    "choices": [
      "Grecanico",
      "Gregorio",
      "Romorantin",
      "Fiano"
    ],
    "answer": "Grecanico"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the grape of Chinon Blanc AOP?",
    "choices": [
      "Chardonnay",
      "Sauvignon Gris",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Sauvignon Blanc"
    ],
    "answer": "Chenin Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the grape of Pouilly-sur-Loire?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chasselas",
      "Cabernet Franc",
      "Chenin Blanc"
    ],
    "answer": "Chasselas"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Chardonnay known as in Orl\u00e9ans?",
    "choices": [
      "Romorantin",
      "Auvernat blanc",
      "Melon",
      "Vernatch"
    ],
    "answer": "Auvernat blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Hungary's largest region?",
    "choices": [
      "Tokaji",
      "Sopron",
      "Kunsag",
      "Balanton"
    ],
    "answer": "Kunsag"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the ABV for Vermetino di Gallura Superiore DOCG?",
    "choices": [
      "11 percent",
      "12 percent",
      "13 percent",
      "14 percent"
    ],
    "answer": "13 percent"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Grenache grown in Ch\u00e2teauneuf-du-Pape are required to use what method of vine training?",
    "choices": [
      "Natural selection",
      "VSP",
      "Goblet-trained",
      "Cordon trained"
    ],
    "answer": "Goblet-trained"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What are the unfortified red and white wines bottled under in Banyuls?",
    "choices": [
      "By varietal",
      "Rasteau  AOP",
      "Collioure  AOP",
      "Languedoc  AOP"
    ],
    "answer": "Collioure  AOP"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "How long has Brandy de Jerez labled \"solera reserva\" be aged for?",
    "choices": [
      "1 year",
      "3 years",
      "5 years",
      "10 years"
    ],
    "answer": "3 years"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What producers makes Barca Velha?",
    "choices": [
      "Calems",
      "Ferreira",
      "Neipoort",
      "Dows"
    ],
    "answer": "Ferreira"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Grand Maupertuis & Petit Maupertui are found where?",
    "choices": [
      "Provence",
      "Vosne-Roman\u00e9e",
      "Clos de Vougeout",
      "Champagne"
    ],
    "answer": "Clos de Vougeout"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which is a 5th growth of Margaux?",
    "choices": [
      "Chateau Palmer",
      "Chateau Lynch-Bages",
      "Chateau du Tertre",
      "Chateau du Toulouse"
    ],
    "answer": "Chateau du tertre, Ch\u00e2teau dauzac"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the max. residual sugar for a ros\u00e9 from Marsannay?",
    "choices": [
      "0 grams per liter of residual sugar",
      "2 grams per liter of residual sugar",
      "3 grams per liter of residual sugar",
      "5 grams per liter of residual sugar"
    ],
    "answer": "3 grams per liter of residual sugar"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the most widely planted varietal in the Cote Chalonaise?",
    "choices": [
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris",
      "Aligote"
    ],
    "answer": "Pinot Noir"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Producers of Mazoy\u00e8res-Chambertin may also label their wines as what?",
    "choices": [
      "Charmes-Chambertin",
      "Vosne-Roman\u00e9e",
      "Savigny-l\u00e8s-Beaune",
      "Chapelle-Chambertin"
    ],
    "answer": "Charmes-Chambertin"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the synonym for Sangiovese on Corsica?",
    "choices": [
      "Nevers",
      "Folle Blanche",
      "Nosolia",
      "Nielluccio"
    ],
    "answer": "Nielluccio"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which mountian range dominates the center of Romania?",
    "choices": [
      "Dentelles",
      "Catskills",
      "Alps",
      "Carpathian"
    ],
    "answer": "Carpathian"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which greek varietal has clonal offspring identified by the colors black, white & blonde?",
    "choices": [
      "Greek blanc",
      "Moschofilero",
      "Muscadet",
      "Mateus"
    ],
    "answer": "Moschofilero"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which AVA is more notherly: Rockpile or Dry Creek Valley?",
    "choices": [
      "Rockpile",
      "Dry Creek Valley",
      "both are on the same latitude",
      "neither are to the north"
    ],
    "answer": "Rockpile"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the name of the wind that influences the climate of Argentina?",
    "choices": [
      "Freemantle doctor",
      "Heavenly winds",
      "Cape Doctor",
      "Zonda"
    ],
    "answer": "Zonda"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Manischewitz concord grape wine must contain what % of concord grapes in it?",
    "choices": [
      "25",
      "51",
      "75",
      "100"
    ],
    "answer": "51"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which area is more northerly: Ribbon Ridge or Eola Amity Hills?",
    "choices": [
      "Eola Amity Hills",
      "Ribbon Ridge",
      "both are equal",
      "neither are not real appellations"
    ],
    "answer": "Ribbon Ridge"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Bodegas Chacra located?",
    "choices": [
      "Puente Alto, Chile",
      "Mosel, Germany",
      "Patagonia, Argentina",
      "Umbria, Italy"
    ],
    "answer": "Patagonia, Argentina"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the most planted grape in British Columbia?",
    "choices": [
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Merlot",
      "Sauvignon Blanc"
    ],
    "answer": "Merlot"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is Napa Valley's oldest winery?",
    "choices": [
      "Gallo",
      "Rodney Strong",
      "Kendall Jackson",
      "Charles Krug"
    ],
    "answer": "Charles Krug"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "A vineyard designated wine from napa must contain what % of that vineyard?",
    "choices": [
      "75",
      "85",
      "95",
      "100"
    ],
    "answer": "95"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What South American country is home to Moet and Chandon?",
    "choices": [
      "Chile",
      "Argentina",
      "Brazil",
      "Peru"
    ],
    "answer": "Brazil"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the mountain range of the southern Rhone Valley?",
    "choices": [
      "Dordogne",
      "Dentelles",
      "Rockies",
      "Alps"
    ],
    "answer": "Dentelles"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the river that the Die appellation resides on?",
    "choices": [
      "Hudson",
      "Po",
      "Dordogne",
      "Drome"
    ],
    "answer": "Drome"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is ch\u00e2teau Bouscaut located?",
    "choices": [
      "Graves",
      "Germany",
      "Gouges",
      "Haut Poitou"
    ],
    "answer": "Graves"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is the Ararat Valley?",
    "choices": [
      "Italy",
      "Azerbaijan",
      "Spain",
      "Armenia"
    ],
    "answer": "Armenia"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where would you most likely find the Vilana grape?",
    "choices": [
      "Cassanovia",
      "Pantelleria",
      "Crete",
      "France"
    ],
    "answer": "Crete"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where would you find the Xynisteri grape?",
    "choices": [
      "Crete",
      "Cyprus",
      "Algeria",
      "Italy"
    ],
    "answer": "Cyprus"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What does edes mean on a Hungarian wine label?",
    "choices": [
      "Dry",
      "Sweet",
      "White grapes",
      "Riesling"
    ],
    "answer": "Sweet"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the grape of Cotnari?",
    "choices": [
      "Grenache",
      "Vidal",
      "Merlot",
      "Grasa"
    ],
    "answer": "Grasa"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Who produces Charles de Gaulle Champagne?",
    "choices": [
      "Gouget",
      "Drappier",
      "Dordogne",
      "Gossett"
    ],
    "answer": "Drappier"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Who produces Quinta do Faz?",
    "choices": [
      "Churchills",
      "Calem",
      "Conklins",
      "Neipoort"
    ],
    "answer": "Calem"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where is Avize?",
    "choices": [
      "Portugal",
      "Champagne",
      "Jura",
      "Burgundy"
    ],
    "answer": "Champagne"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What is the minimum ABV for port wine?",
    "choices": [
      "25 percent",
      "16 percent",
      "19 percent",
      "5 percent"
    ],
    "answer": "19 percent"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "How long is the minimum aging for VVO port wine?",
    "choices": [
      "10 years",
      "40 years",
      "70 years",
      "80 years"
    ],
    "answer": "80 years"
  }
];

//questions2

[
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the region of Stellenbosch located?",
    choices: [
      "South Africa",
      "South Australia",
      "Southern Chile",
      "Southern Portugal"
    ],
    answer: "South Africa"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What are the 2 departments of Alsace?",
    choices: [
      "North and South",
      "East and West",
      "Haut and Bas",
      "Sud and Ouest"
    ],
    answer: "Haut and Bas"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which is not a noble grape of Alsace?",
    choices: [
      "Riesling",
      "Pinot Gris",
      "Muscat",
      "Merlot"
    ],
    answer: "Merlot"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which region is home to the city of Strousbourg?",
    choices: [
      "Alsace"
    ],
    answer: "Alsace"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which region sits on the border of Germany?",
    choices: [
      "Alsace",
      "Burgundy",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Jura"
    ],
    answer: "Alsace"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "In which region will you find S\u00e9lection de Grains Nobles on the label?",
    choices: [
      "Alsace",
      "Burgundy",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Jura"
    ],
    answer: "Alsace"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is the main red grape of Alsace?",
    choices: [
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Cabernet Franc",
      "Poulsard",
      "Grenache"
    ],
    answer: "Pinot Noir"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Local specialties vin jaune and vin de paille can be found where?",
    choices: [
      "Jura",
      "Champagne",
      "Burgundy",
      "Bordeaux"
    ],
    answer: "Jura"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the region of L\u2019Etoile?",
    choices: [
      "Jura",
      "Champagne",
      "Burgundy",
      "Bordeaux"
    ],
    answer: "Jura"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What Champagne house is associated with Dom Perignon?",
    choices: [
      "Drappier",
      "Moet & Chandon",
      "Selosse",
      "Veuve Cliquot"
    ],
    answer: "Moet & Chandon"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Santa Rita Hills AVA?",
    choices: [
      "Oregon",
      "California",
      "New York",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    answer: "California"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is chapitalization?",
    choices: [
      "Adding water to fermenting wine",
      "adding sugar to the fermenting wine",
      "taking water away from wine at bottling",
      "using a screw cap enclosure"
    ],
    answer: "adding sugar to the fermenting wine"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What contribution is Louis Pasteur responsible for?",
    choices: [
      "harvest science",
      "varietal science",
      "water table management",
      "fermentation science"
    ],
    answer: "fermentation science"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Algarve region?",
    choices: [
      "South Africa",
      "South Australia",
      "Southern Chile",
      "Southern Portugal"
    ],
    answer: "Southern Portugal"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is the main grape of the Gigondas region?",
    choices: [
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Cabernet Franc",
      "Poulsard",
      "Grenache"
    ],
    answer: "Grenache"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which region is known for their ros\u00e9 production?",
    choices: [
      "Bordeaux",
      "Burgundy",
      "Alsace",
      "Provence"
    ],
    answer: "Provence"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which region is known for their Pinot Noir production?",
    choices: [
      "Bordeaux",
      "Burgundy",
      "Alsace",
      "Provence"
    ],
    answer: "Burgundy"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which grape is known for its resemblance to Cabernet Sauvignon?",
    choices: [
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Cabernet Franc",
      "Poulsard",
      "Grenache"
    ],
    answer: "Cabernet Franc"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Willamette Valley?",
    choices: [
      "Oregon",
      "California",
      "New York",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    answer: "Oregon"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Long Island AVA?",
    choices: [
      "Oregon",
      "California",
      "New York",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    answer: "New York"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is Sancerre located?",
    choices: [
      "Loire Valley",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Burgundy",
      "Champagne"
    ],
    answer: "Loire Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where would you find the 1855 classification?",
    choices: [
      "Loire Valley",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Burgundy",
      "Champagne"
    ],
    answer: "Bordeaux"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the McLaren Vale wine region?",
    choices: [
      "South Africa",
      "South Australia",
      "Southern Chile",
      "Southern Portugal"
    ],
    answer: "South Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Hermitage region?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Provence",
      "Champagne",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Rh\u00f4ne Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Condrieu region?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Provence",
      "Champagne",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Rh\u00f4ne Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which region is La Grande Dame produced in?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Provence",
      "Champagne",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Champagne"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the region of Paarl?",
    choices: [
      "South Africa",
      "South Australia",
      "Southern Chile",
      "Southern Portugal"
    ],
    answer: "South Africa"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Columbia Valley AVA?",
    choices: [
      "Oregon",
      "California",
      "New York",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    answer: "Washington State"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Red Mountain AVA?",
    choices: [
      "Oregon",
      "California",
      "New York",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    answer: "Washington State"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is Ch\u00e2teauneuf-du-Pape AOP?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Provence",
      "Champagne",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Rh\u00f4ne Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Vouvray region?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Provence",
      "Champagne",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Loire Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the city of Reims located?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Provence",
      "Champagne",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Champagne"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the city of Nice located?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Provence",
      "Champagne",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Provence"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Melon de Borgogne grape found?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Provence",
      "Burgundy",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Loire Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What grape is most associated with Napa Valley?",
    choices: [
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Grenache",
      "Riesling",
      "Malbec"
    ],
    answer: "Cabernet Sauvignon"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What grape is most associated with Mendoza, Argentina?",
    choices: [
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Grenache",
      "Riesling",
      "Malbec"
    ],
    answer: "Malbec"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is Schloss Johannisberg?",
    choices: [
      "France",
      "Germany",
      "Austria",
      "Hungary"
    ],
    answer: "Germany"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which country is associated with Liebfraumilch?",
    choices: [
      "France",
      "Germany",
      "Austria",
      "Hungary"
    ],
    answer: "Germany"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the region of Tokaj found?",
    choices: [
      "France",
      "Germany",
      "Austria",
      "Hungary"
    ],
    answer: "Hungary"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where would you most likely find \"Doctor\" on a wine label?",
    choices: [
      "France",
      "Germany",
      "Austria",
      "Hungary"
    ],
    answer: "Germany"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What grape is most associated with the Rheingau?",
    choices: [
      "Chardonnay",
      "Grenache",
      "Riesling",
      "Malbec"
    ],
    answer: "Reisling"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Horse Heaven Hills AVA?",
    choices: [
      "Oregon",
      "California",
      "New York",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    answer: "Washington State"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which grape is most likely grown in a cooler climate?",
    choices: [
      "Viognier",
      "Grenache",
      "Riesling",
      "Malbec"
    ],
    answer: "Riesling"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which grape is most likely grown near Grenache and Syrah vines?",
    choices: [
      "Viognier",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Nebbiolo",
      "Malbec"
    ],
    answer: "Viognier"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is an anbaugebiet?",
    choices: [
      "German region",
      "Alsatian lake",
      "French mountians",
      "Oregon hills"
    ],
    answer: "German region"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Wachau wine region?",
    choices: [
      "France",
      "Germany",
      "Austria",
      "Hungary"
    ],
    answer: "Austria"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which grape is most associated with Pouilly-Fume?",
    choices: [
      "Viognier",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Nebbiolo",
      "Pinot Noir"
    ],
    answer: "Sauvignon Blanc"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which grape is mostly associated with the Barbaresco wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Merlot",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Nebbiolo",
      "Pinot Noir"
    ],
    answer: "Nebbiolo"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which grape is mostly associated with the Medoc wine growing area?",
    choices: [
      "Cabernet Sauvignon",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Nebbiolo",
      "Pinot Noir"
    ],
    answer: "Cabernet Sauvignon"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What mountain range protects Alsace?",
    choices: [
      "Dentelles",
      "Vosges",
      "Alps",
      "Massif Central"
    ],
    answer: "Vosges"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Colmar?",
    choices: [
      "Bordeaux",
      "Burgundy",
      "Alsace",
      "Provence"
    ],
    answer: "Alsace"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What is gr\u00e9s de Vosges?",
    choices: [
      "Weather pattern in Bordeaux",
      "Soil in Alsace",
      "Mountain range in Jura",
      "Lake in Savoie"
    ],
    answer: "Soil in Alsace"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What grape may be included in the bottle if an Alsatian wine says Pinot Blanc?",
    choices: [
      "Auxerrois",
      "Aligote",
      "Rousette",
      "Melon Blanc"
    ],
    answer: "Auxerrois"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Tokay d\u2019Alsace was once a common name for what grape?",
    choices: [
      "Pinot Gris",
      "Aligote",
      "Rousette",
      "Melon Blanc"
    ],
    answer: "Pinot Gris"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Kanzlerberg?",
    choices: [
      "Alsace",
      "Lorraine",
      "Provence",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Alsace"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Cotes de toul resides in which larger growing AOP?",
    choices: [
      "Jura",
      "Lorraine",
      "Provence",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Lorraine"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which is not a main grape of the Jura?",
    choices: [
      "Poulsard",
      "Trousseau",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Aligote"
    ],
    answer: "Aligote"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which region may not produce vin de paille?",
    choices: [
      "Arbois",
      "L'Etoile",
      "Macvin du Jura",
      "C\u00f4tes du Jura"
    ],
    answer: "Macvin du Jura"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Lake Bourget?",
    choices: [
      "Bordeaux",
      "Savoie",
      "Alsace",
      "Moselle"
    ],
    answer: "Savoie"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where are the Brokenback Mountains?",
    choices: [
      "Albany",
      "Hunter",
      "Gisbourne",
      "Margaret River"
    ],
    answer: "Hunter"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Tyrrell\u2019s Vat 1 is made in which appellation?",
    choices: [
      "Hunter Valley",
      "Mornington Peninsula",
      "Canberra District",
      "Barossa Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Hunter Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which region is shared between New South Wales and the Australian Capital Territory?",
    choices: [
      "Mornington Peninsula",
      "Canberra District",
      "Barossa Valley",
      "Hunter Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Canberra District"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which region does the Port Phillip Bay influence?",
    choices: [
      "Mornington Peninsula",
      "Canberra District",
      "Orange",
      "Southern Highlands"
    ],
    answer: "Mornington Peninsula"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which AVA is not in San Luis Obispo County?",
    choices: [
      "Paso Robles",
      "Arroyo Grande",
      "North Yuba",
      "Edna Valley"
    ],
    answer: "North Yuba"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which area is not in Ontario?",
    choices: [
      "Niagara Peninsula",
      "Lake Erie North Shore",
      "Pelee Island",
      "Frasier Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Frasier Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which is a synonym Chardonnay in Switzerland?",
    choices: [
      "Morillon",
      "Melon Blanc",
      "Romorantin",
      "Moscatel"
    ],
    answer: "Morillon"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Ch\u00e2teau Chalon AOP?",
    choices: [
      "Jura",
      "Champagne",
      "Burgundy",
      "Bordeaux"
    ],
    answer: "Jura"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which region ripens first?",
    choices: [
      "Alsace",
      "Burgundy",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Jura"
    ],
    answer: "Alsace"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which area is in British Columbia?",
    choices: [
      "Niagara Peninsula",
      "Lake Erie North Shore",
      "Pelee Island",
      "Frasier Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Frasier Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which region is closest in proximaty to the Cognac region?",
    choices: [
      "Bordeaux",
      "Burgundy",
      "Alsace",
      "Provence"
    ],
    answer: "Bordeaux"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What is the main grape of the Cornas region?",
    choices: [
      "Grenache",
      "Syrah",
      "Mourvedre",
      "Cinsault"
    ],
    answer: "Syrah"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What is the main grape of the C\u00f4te-R\u00f4tie region?",
    choices: [
      "Grenache",
      "Syrah",
      "Mourvedre",
      "Cinsault"
    ],
    answer: "Syrah"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Palette?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Provence",
      "Champagne",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Provence"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is St. Bris AOP?",
    choices: [
      "Alsace",
      "Burgundy",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Jura"
    ],
    answer: "Burgundy"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Passe-Tout-Grains produced?",
    choices: [
      "Alsace",
      "Burgundy",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Jura"
    ],
    answer: "Burgundy"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Barsac AOP?",
    choices: [
      "Alsace",
      "Burgundy",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Jura"
    ],
    answer: "Bordeaux"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What is the minimum ABV % for Pomerol wines?",
    choices: [
      "10",
      "11",
      "12",
      "13"
    ],
    answer: "11"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Ajaccio AOP?",
    choices: [
      "Alsace",
      "Corsica",
      "Bordeaux",
      "Jura"
    ],
    answer: "Corsica"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Monticello AVA?",
    choices: [
      "Oregon",
      "Virginia",
      "New York",
      "Ohio"
    ],
    answer: "Virginia"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Central Coast AVA?",
    choices: [
      "Oregon",
      "California",
      "New York",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    answer: "California"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What grape is most likely growing in Ribbon Ridge?",
    choices: [
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Cabernet Franc",
      "Merlot",
      "Grenache"
    ],
    answer: "Pinot Noir"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Bergerac AOP?",
    choices: [
      "Southern Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Provence",
      "SW France",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "SW France"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Monbazillac?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Western Provence",
      "SW France",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "SW France"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Cour-Cheverny?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Western Provence",
      "SW France",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Loire Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Chateau Grillet?",
    choices: [
      "Rh\u00f4ne Valley",
      "Western Provence",
      "SW France",
      "Loire Valley"
    ],
    answer: "Rh\u00f4ne Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Greco di Tufo DOCG?",
    choices: [
      "Tuscany",
      "Abruzzo",
      "Campania",
      "Piedmont"
    ],
    answer: "Campania"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Taurasi DOCG?",
    choices: [
      "Tuscany",
      "Abruzzo",
      "Campania",
      "Piedmont"
    ],
    answer: "Campania"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where would you find the Dolcetto grape growing?",
    choices: [
      "Tuscany",
      "Abruzzo",
      "Campania",
      "Piedmont"
    ],
    answer: "Piedmont"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where would you find the Fiano grape growing?",
    choices: [
      "Tuscany",
      "Abruzzo",
      "Campania",
      "Piedmont"
    ],
    answer: "Campania"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Geisenheim Wine Institute?",
    choices: [
      "France",
      "Germany",
      "Austria",
      "Hungary"
    ],
    answer: "Germany"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Lake Balanton?",
    choices: [
      "France",
      "Germany",
      "Austria",
      "Hungary"
    ],
    answer: "Hungary"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Goldtr\u00f6pfchen vineyard?",
    choices: [
      "Rheingau",
      "Mosel",
      "Rheinhessen",
      "Nahe"
    ],
    answer: "Mosel"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the \u00dcrziger W\u00fcrzgarten vineyard?",
    choices: [
      "Rheingau",
      "Mosel",
      "Rheinhessen",
      "Nahe"
    ],
    answer: "Mosel"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which region does the Eifel Mountains influence?",
    choices: [
      "Rheingau",
      "Mosel",
      "Ahr",
      "Nahe"
    ],
    answer: "Ahr"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Sp\u00e4tburgunder is a synonym for which grape in Germany?",
    choices: [
      "Grenache",
      "Syrah",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Cinsault"
    ],
    answer: "Pinot Noir"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the bocksbeutel bottle utilized?",
    choices: [
      "Rheingau",
      "Baden",
      "Ahr",
      "Franken"
    ],
    answer: "Franken"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What does trocken indicate on a German wine label?",
    choices: [
      "Sweet",
      "Dry",
      "Sparkling",
      "Aged"
    ],
    answer: "Dry"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where would you find the designation Districtus Austriae Controllatus (DAC)?",
    choices: [
      "France",
      "Germany",
      "Austria",
      "Hungary"
    ],
    answer: "Austria"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What city would you find Wiener Gemischter Satz being produced?",
    choices: [
      "Budapest",
      "Venice",
      "Vienna",
      "Berlin"
    ],
    answer: "Vienna"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which is not a subregion of the Douro Valley?",
    choices: [
      "Baixo Corgo",
      "Cima Corgo",
      "Douro Superior",
      "Minho Superior"
    ],
    answer: "Minho Superior"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which region is guarded by a \"rain shadow\" effect of the local mountains?",
    choices: [
      "Bordeaux",
      "Alsace",
      "Champagne",
      "Provence"
    ],
    answer: "Alsace"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is the synonym for Chasselas in Alsace?",
    choices: [
      "Gutedel",
      "Roussette",
      "Fiano",
      "Melon Blanc"
    ],
    answer: "Gutedel"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is the synonym for Pinot Blanc in Alsace?",
    choices: [
      "Klevner",
      "Gutedel",
      "Melon Blanc",
      "Roussette"
    ],
    answer: "Klevner"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Which year was Kaefferkopf added to the Grand Cru list in Alsace?",
    choices: [
      "2002",
      "2004",
      "2007",
      "2009"
    ],
    answer: "2007"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is the % of minimum potential alcohol for Reisling in Alsace Grand Cru AOP?",
    choices: [
      "11",
      "12.5",
      "13.5",
      "14"
    ],
    answer: "11"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What grape is Vorbourg Grand Cru made with?",
    choices: [
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Reisling",
      "Pinot gris"
    ],
    answer: "Pinot Noir"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is the minimum ABV % for Cr\u00e9mant du Jura?",
    choices: [
      "8",
      "9",
      "10",
      "11"
    ],
    answer: "9"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is the minimum time in oak (months) for Macvin du Jura?",
    choices: [
      "6",
      "10",
      "12",
      "24"
    ],
    answer: "10"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Can a producer chapitalize vin de paille in the Jura in poor vintages?",
    choices: [
      "Yes",
      "No",
      "With AOP Permission",
      "2 times every decade"
    ],
    answer: "No"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is the grape of Chignin-Bergeron?",
    choices: [
      "Marsanne",
      "Roussane",
      "Grenache Blanc",
      "Chardonnay"
    ],
    answer: "Roussane"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What years was the Australia Wine and Brandy Corporation founded?",
    choices: [
      "1971",
      "1981",
      "1991",
      "2001"
    ],
    answer: "1981"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Which AOP does not produce Muscat de Noel?",
    choices: [
      "Muscat de Rivesaltes",
      "Muscat de Saint-Jean-de-Minervois",
      "Muscat de Frontignan",
      "Muscat de Lunel"
    ],
    answer: "Muscat de Frontignan"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Which producer is not in Bandol?",
    choices: [
      "Domaine Tempier",
      "Ch\u00e2teau de Pibarnon",
      "Domaine Ott",
      "Ch\u00e2teau Pradeaux"
    ],
    answer: "Domaine Ott"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Which area is not in Okanagan Valley?",
    choices: [
      "Golden Mile",
      "Black Sage/Osoyoos",
      "Pelee Island",
      "Naramata"
    ],
    answer: "Pelee Island"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is Centerbe?",
    choices: [
      "Dry cider from Tuscany",
      "Herbal liquer Abruzzo",
      "Sweet wine from Elba",
      "White grape from Campania"
    ],
    answer: "Herbal liquer Abruzzo"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is the minimum ABV % for Ch\u00e2teauneuf-du-Pape AOP?",
    choices: [
      "11.5",
      "12.5",
      "13.5",
      "14"
    ],
    answer: "12.5"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Which region is planted En Ligne and Au Carr\u00e9?",
    choices: [
      "Hermitage",
      "Ch\u00e2teauneuf-du-Pape",
      "Condrieu",
      "St-Joseph"
    ],
    answer: "Ch\u00e2teauneuf-du-Pape"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What grape is known as Malvoisie de Corse?",
    choices: [
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Vermentino",
      "Reisling",
      "Picoutener"
    ],
    answer: "Vermentino"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is Ros\u00e9 des Riceys made from?",
    choices: [
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Cabernet Franc",
      "Reisling",
      "Picoutener"
    ],
    answer: "Pinot Noir"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Which grape is most likely found in Rosette AOC?",
    choices: [
      "Gutedel",
      "Roussette",
      "Fiano",
      "Sauvignon Blanc"
    ],
    answer: "Sauvignon Blanc"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is Ortonoa DOC?",
    choices: [
      "Tuscany",
      "Abruzzo",
      "Campania",
      "Piedmont"
    ],
    answer: "Abruzzo"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is the minimum % of Montelpuciano in Colline Teramane?",
    choices: [
      "80",
      "85",
      "90",
      "95"
    ],
    answer: "90"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where would you find the Ruch\u00e8 grape growing?",
    choices: [
      "Tuscany",
      "Abruzzo",
      "Campania",
      "Piedmont"
    ],
    answer: "Piedmont"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "If a German wine label has a grape variety on it, what % of that grape must be in the bottle?",
    choices: [
      "80",
      "85",
      "90",
      "95"
    ],
    answer: "85"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Orsteil of Eitelsbach?",
    choices: [
      "Rheingau",
      "Mosel",
      "Rheinhessen",
      "Nahe"
    ],
    answer: "Mosel"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is Erbacher Marcobrunn located?",
    choices: [
      "Rheingau",
      "Mosel",
      "Rheinhessen",
      "Nahe"
    ],
    answer: "Rheingau"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Which wine region has an area known as the Roter Hang?",
    choices: [
      "Rheingau",
      "Mosel",
      "Rheinhessen",
      "Nahe"
    ],
    answer: "Rheinhessen"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Which region does Meyer-N\u00e4kel prodcue wine in?",
    choices: [
      "Rheingau",
      "Mosel",
      "Ahr",
      "Nahe"
    ],
    answer: "Ahr"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Who produces Quinta do Bomfim?",
    choices: [
      "Churchills",
      "Dows",
      "Calem",
      "Delaforce"
    ],
    answer: "Dows"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Who produces Quinta do Panascal?",
    choices: [
      "Churchills",
      "Dows",
      "Calem",
      "Fonseca"
    ],
    answer: "Fonseca"
  }
  [
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Hawkes Bay wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "New Zealand"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Margaret River wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Pinotage grape most likley grown?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "South Africa"
    ],
    answer: "South Africa"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which grape is most likely grown in Barossa Valley?",
    choices: [
      "Vidal",
      "Shiraz",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Pinotage"
    ],
    answer: "Shiraz"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which grape is most likely grown in McLaren Vale?",
    choices: [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Shiraz",
      "Pinot Noir",
      "Pinotage"
    ],
    answer: "Shiraz"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Patagonia wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Argentina"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Maipo Valley wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Chile"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What country is Almaviva produced in?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Chile"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Santorini wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "Bulgaria"
    ],
    answer: "Greece"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is botrytis cinerea?",
    choices: [
      "a vineyard mushroom",
      "a fungus",
      "a yeast strain",
      "the Latin god of wine"
    ],
    answer: "a fungus"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the VQA found?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Canada"
    ],
    answer: "Canada"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Lake Erie North Shore found?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Canada"
    ],
    answer: "Canada"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Valle de Guadalupe?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "Mexico",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Mexico"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Coonawara wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is the main grape used for the wines of Cornas?",
    choices: [
      "Grenache",
      "Syrah",
      "Merlot",
      "Cabernet Sauvignon"
    ],
    answer: "Syrah"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is the main grape used for the wines of C\u00f4te-R\u00f4tie?",
    choices: [
      "Grenache",
      "Syrah",
      "Merlot",
      "Cabernet Sauvignon"
    ],
    answer: "Syrah"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is the main grape used for the wines of Gigondas?",
    choices: [
      "Grenache",
      "Syrah",
      "Merlot",
      "Cabernet Sauvignon"
    ],
    answer: "Grenache"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is the main grape used for the wines of Pomerol?",
    choices: [
      "Grenache",
      "Syrah",
      "Merlot",
      "Cabernet Sauvignon"
    ],
    answer: "Merlot"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which country would Cr\u00e9mant sparkling wines be found in?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "France"
    ],
    answer: "France"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Which country would Sancerre be found in?",
    choices: [
      "England",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "France"
    ],
    answer: "France"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is the German tern for \"dry\"?",
    choices: [
      "grosslage",
      "trocken",
      "tresterbrand",
      "winzer"
    ],
    answer: "trocken"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Pfalz wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Germany",
      "France"
    ],
    answer: "Germany"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Nahe wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Germany",
      "France"
    ],
    answer: "Germany"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Baden wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Germany",
      "France"
    ],
    answer: "Germany"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Franken wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Germany",
      "France"
    ],
    answer: "Germany"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Ahr wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Germany",
      "France"
    ],
    answer: "Germany"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "What is the synonym for Pinot Noir in Germany?",
    choices: [
      "Pinot Gris",
      "Sp\u00e4tburgunder",
      "Septime",
      "Johannisberg"
    ],
    answer: "Sp\u00e4tburgunder"
  },
  {
    level: "easy",
    question: "Where is the Zempl\u00e9n wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Germany",
      "France"
    ],
    answer: "Hungary"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Auckland wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "New Zealand"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Mornington Peninsula wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Torront\u00e9s grape most likley grown?",
    choices: [
      "Spain",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Argentina"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Shoalhaven Coast wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Kumeu wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "USA"
    ],
    answer: "New Zealand"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Gisbourne wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Bannockburn wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "New Zealand"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Limestone Coast wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "USA"
    ],
    answer: "Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Yarra Valley wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Luj\u00e1n de Cuyo wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Spain",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Argentina"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where are the Criolla Grande and Cereza grapes most prevalent?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Argentina"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Vi\u00f1edo Chadwick produced?",
    choices: [
      "Uruguay",
      "Spain",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Chile"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Who produces Clos Apalta?",
    choices: [
      "Montes",
      "Torres",
      "Casa Lapostolle",
      "Concha Y Toro"
    ],
    answer: "Casa Lapostolle"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Who produces Don Melchor?",
    choices: [
      "Montes",
      "Torres",
      "Casa Lapostolle",
      "Concha Y Toro"
    ],
    answer: "Concha Y Toro"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which grape is found in Chile more than it is found in Argentina?",
    choices: [
      "Merlot",
      "Carmen\u00e8re",
      "Syrah",
      "Pinot Noir"
    ],
    answer: "Carmen\u00e8re"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Uco Valley?",
    choices: [
      "San Juan",
      "Mendoza",
      "Maipo",
      "Santiago"
    ],
    answer: "Mendoza"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Retsina produced?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "Bulgaria"
    ],
    answer: "Greece"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Paros wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "Bulgaria"
    ],
    answer: "Greece"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where are the islands of Lemnos and Rhodes?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "Bulgaria"
    ],
    answer: "Greece"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Which mountain range impacts the Tokaj regoin?",
    choices: [
      "Alps",
      "Carpathian",
      "Dentelles",
      "Dolomite"
    ],
    answer: "Carpathian"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where would you find R\u00e1k\u00f3czy\u2019s original classification?",
    choices: [
      "Tokaj",
      "Andorra",
      "Sopron",
      "Andalucia"
    ],
    answer: "Tokaj"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is Egri Bikav\u00e9r produced?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "Bulgaria"
    ],
    answer: "Hungary"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Great Southern wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "USA"
    ],
    answer: "Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Gaillac wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Provence",
      "Languedoc",
      "Rousillon",
      "SW France"
    ],
    answer: "SW France"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Madiran wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Provence",
      "Languedoc",
      "Rousillon",
      "SW France"
    ],
    answer: "SW France"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Monbazillac wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Provence",
      "Languedoc",
      "Rousillon",
      "SW France"
    ],
    answer: "SW France"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "Where is the Gaillac wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Provence",
      "Languedoc",
      "Rousillon",
      "SW France"
    ],
    answer: "SW France"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Monbazillac?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Sweet White"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Cahors?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry Red"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Carmignano?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry Red"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Bardolino Superiore?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry Red"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Soave Superiore?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry White"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Nobile di Montepulciano?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry Red"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Cerasuolo di Vittoria DOCG?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry Red"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Valtellina Superiore?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry Red"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in C\u00f2nero Riserva DOCG?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry Red"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Arbois?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "All of these"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in l'Etoile?",
    choices: [
      "Vin Jaune",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "All of these"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Cornas?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry Red"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Ch\u00e2teau-Grillet?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry White"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What is the maximum residual sugar % found in Cr\u00e9mant de Die?",
    choices: [
      "12 g/l",
      "15 g/l",
      "21 g/l",
      "33 g/l"
    ],
    answer: "15 g/l"
  },
  {
    level: "medium",
    question: "What is Edelf\u00e4ule the Germanic term for?",
    choices: [
      "single vineyard",
      "noble rot",
      "cooperative producer",
      "hand harvest"
    ],
    answer: "noble rot"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Aconcagua wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Chile"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Big Rivers wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "USA"
    ],
    answer: "Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Langton's Classification utilized?",
    choices: [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "Argentina",
      "USA"
    ],
    answer: "Australia"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Waimakariri and Waipara rivers most influencial?",
    choices: [
      "North Island NZ",
      "South Island NZ",
      "Western Australia",
      "South Australia"
    ],
    answer: "South Island NZ"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Southern Alps and Lake Wanaka most influencial?",
    choices: [
      "North Island NZ",
      "South Island NZ",
      "Western Australia",
      "South Australia"
    ],
    answer: "South Island NZ"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is Vale dos Vinhedos?",
    choices: [
      "Uruguay",
      "Brazil",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Brazil"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is the synonym for Tannat in Uruguay?",
    choices: [
      "Criolla",
      "Harriague",
      "Pinotage",
      "Breton"
    ],
    answer: "Harriague"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Cephalonia wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "Bulgaria"
    ],
    answer: "Greece"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Sterea Ellada wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "Bulgaria"
    ],
    answer: "Greece"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Samos wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "Bulgaria"
    ],
    answer: "Greece"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where would you find the Szarvas and M\u00e9zes M\u00e1ly vineyards?",
    choices: [
      "Balanton",
      "Tokaj",
      "Sopron",
      "Kunsag"
    ],
    answer: "Tokaj"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What is a g\u00f6nc?",
    choices: [
      "a wine barrel in Argentina",
      "a yeast strain in Hungary",
      "a wine barrel in Tokaj",
      "a glass bottle in Slovenia"
    ],
    answer: "a wine barrel in Tokaj"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is Kir\u00e1lyudvar from?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Romania",
      "Bulgaria"
    ],
    answer: "Hungary"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is Santo Tom\u00e1s?",
    choices: [
      "Uruguay",
      "Mexico",
      "Argentina",
      "Chile"
    ],
    answer: "Mexico"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is Polish Hill?",
    choices: [
      "Barossa Valley",
      "Clare Valley",
      "Yarra Valley",
      "Tasmania"
    ],
    answer: "Clare Valley"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Which is not a lieu-dits of Cornas?",
    choices: [
      "Les Reynards",
      "La C\u00f4te",
      "Les Clos",
      "Les Mazards"
    ],
    answer: "Les Clos"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Buzet wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Provence",
      "Languedoc",
      "Rousillon",
      "SW France"
    ],
    answer: "SW France"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Carmignano?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry Red"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "What style of wine is produced in Vernaccia di San Gimignano?",
    choices: [
      "Dry Red",
      "Dry White",
      "Sweet White",
      "All of these"
    ],
    answer: "Dry White"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where would you find Neyret-Gachet on the wine label?",
    choices: [
      "Ch\u00e2teau Chalon",
      "Ch\u00e2teau-Grillet",
      "Ch\u00e2teau Couhins",
      "Ch\u00e2teau Charmes"
    ],
    answer: "Ch\u00e2teau-Grillet"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Grosser Ring?",
    choices: [
      "Rheingau",
      "Mosel",
      "Rhenhessen",
      "Nahe"
    ],
    answer: "Mosel"
  },
  {
    level: "hard",
    question: "Where is the Zempl\u00e9n wine region?",
    choices: [
      "Greece",
      "Hungary",
      "Germany",
      "France"
    ],
    answer: "Hungary"
  }

[
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Vouvray?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Chenin Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Sancerre?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Sauvignon Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Champagne?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Chardonnay"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Bordeaux?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Sauvignon Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Chablis?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Chardonnay"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Valencia wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Ribera del Duero wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Rioja wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the R\u00edas Baixas  wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Priorat wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Barolo wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Brunello di Montalcino wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Barbaresco wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Amarone della Valpolicella wine from?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Friuli wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Chianti Classico wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is thecountry that Prosecco comes from?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which is the country you would most likely find Tempranillo in?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which is the country you would most likely find Sangiovese in?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Which is the country you would most likely find Nebbiolo in?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Seneca Lake wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "Australia",
      "UK",
      "New Zealand",
      "USA"
    ],
    "answer": "USA"
  },
  {
    "level": "easy",
    "question": "Where is the Yamhill-Carlton District wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "Australia",
      "UK",
      "New Zealand",
      "USA"
    ],
    "answer": "USA"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Chinon?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Chenin Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Pouilly-Fume?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Sauvignon Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Cote Chalonais?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Chardonnay"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Graves?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Sauvignon Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which country has the most Cabernet Sauvignon under vine?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "USA",
      "Australia",
      "Spain"
    ],
    "answer": "USA"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which country has the least Cabernet Sauvignon under vine?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "USA",
      "Australia",
      "Spain"
    ],
    "answer": "Australia"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Sauternes?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Sauvignon Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Pened\u00e8s wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Jumilla  wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Montilla-Moriles wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Pened\u00e8s wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Spain"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What style of wine is produced in Rioja?",
    "choices": [
      "Dry white",
      "Dry red",
      "Sparkling wine",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What style of wine is produced in R\u00edas Baixas?",
    "choices": [
      "Dry white",
      "Dry red",
      "Sparkling wine",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What style of wine is produced in Rueda?",
    "choices": [
      "Dry white",
      "Dry red",
      "Sparkling wine",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What style of wine is produced in Valdeorras?",
    "choices": [
      "Dry white",
      "Dry red",
      "Sparkling wine",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Algarve wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Portugal"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Vinho Verde wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Portugal"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the D\u00e3o wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "France",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Portugal"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What style of wine is produced in Vinho Verde?",
    "choices": [
      "Dry white",
      "Dry red",
      "Sparkling wine",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "What style of wine is produced in Douro DOP?",
    "choices": [
      "Dry white",
      "Dry red",
      "Sparkling wine",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Bekaa Valley wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "Lebanon",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Lebanon"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Galilee wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "Lebanon",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Israel"
    ],
    "answer": "Israel"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is Commandaria wine produced?",
    "choices": [
      "Lebanon",
      "Spain",
      "Cyprus",
      "Greece"
    ],
    "answer": "Cyprus"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Uruguay?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Malbec",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Tannat"
    ],
    "answer": "Tannat"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which grape is known as Gamay Blanc in the Jura?",
    "choices": [
      "Chardonnay",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Merlot",
      "Cabernet Franc"
    ],
    "answer": "Chardonnay"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which grape is known as Morillon in the Austria?",
    "choices": [
      "Chardonnay",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Merlot",
      "Cabernet Franc"
    ],
    "answer": "Chardonnay"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Which grape is known as Steen in the South Africa?",
    "choices": [
      "Chardonnay",
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Merlot",
      "Chenin Blanc"
    ],
    "answer": "Chenin Blanc"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the The Rocks of Milton-Freewater wine region?",
    "choices": [
      "Australia",
      "UK",
      "New Zealand",
      "USA"
    ],
    "answer": "USA"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where are the Santa Ynez Mountains?",
    "choices": [
      "California",
      "NY",
      "Oregon",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    "answer": "California"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where are the Mayacamas Mountains?",
    "choices": [
      "California",
      "NY",
      "Oregon",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    "answer": "California"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where are the North Coast Range Mountains?",
    "choices": [
      "California",
      "NY",
      "Oregon",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    "answer": "California"
  },
  {
    "level": "medium",
    "question": "Where is the Shenandoah Valley?",
    "choices": [
      "California",
      "NY",
      "Virginia",
      "Washington State"
    ],
    "answer": "Virginia"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which grape is most associated with Savigny-les-Beaune?",
    "choices": [
      "Sauvignon Blanc",
      "Chenin Blanc",
      "Chardonnay",
      "Pinot Gris"
    ],
    "answer": "Chardonnay"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What style of wine is produced in Ribeiro?",
    "choices": [
      "Dry white",
      "Dry red",
      "Sparkling wine",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Which best describes the wines of Moscatel do Douro?",
    "choices": [
      "Fortified wine",
      "Dry wine",
      "Sparkling wine",
      "Late harvest wine"
    ],
    "answer": "Fortified wine"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "What style of wine is produced in Bairrada?",
    "choices": [
      "Dry white",
      "Dry red",
      "Sparkling wine",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "level": "hard",
    "question": "Where does Chateau Ksara produce wine?",
    "choices": [
      "Lebanon",
      "Spain",
      "Italy",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "answer": "Lebanon"
  }
]

]
]